Mamie Boone papers, Inclusive: 1867-2006, Bulk: 1883-1916, 1952-1960
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Mamie Boone papers
Inclusive: 1867-2006, Bulk: 1883-1916, 1952-1960
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3780
Boone, Mamie
3 document boxes and 1 OVZ box.
Mamie Boone was principal of John H. Reagan Elementary School in Dallas, Texas, during the 1950s. The collection contains few materials on her career as a public educator, but has extensive materials on her travels in Europe and the eastern United States, plus recipes and scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Mamie Boone (1888-1979) was longtime principal of John H. Reagan Elementary School in Dallas, Texas, during the 1950s. Prior to her time at Reagan Elementary, she was principal of James S. Hogg Elementary School, also in Dallas. She served as Vice-President of the Texas Elementary Principals and Supervisors Association in 1922. After a long and distinguished career in public education, she passed away in 1979 and was buried in Laurel Land Memorial Park, Dallas.
Scope and Content
The Mamie Boone papers contain poetry, trip to Europe postcards and scrapbooks, recipes, family and travel photographs, and photographs of the dedication of an elevator on-campus by the NoZe Brotherhood, an unofficial student organization present at Baylor University. The NoZe Brotherhood materials appear to have been mailed to Mamie Boone. Very little of the collection documents Boone's professional career; instead, it documents her leisure time traveling and her personal schoolwork. There are many photographs of various U.S. presidential birthplaces and homes; it was a personal goal of Boone's to visit every presidential birthplace.
The Mary Cole Boone series contains information on Mamie Boone's mother, Mary Cole Boone, (1856-1923) attended Waco University in the 1870s (consolidated with Baylor University in 1886). She married Joseph P. Boone (1851-1934) and moved to Dallas, Texas.
Arrangement
Prior to the current round of processing, the collection was arranged in three boxes and one oversize box. Materials were loose stacks of papers in boxes and plastic bags with no materials in folders and no titles.
Currently, the collection is arranged in five series: I. School and Literary Materials, II. Travel, III. Mary Cole Boone, IV. NoZe Brotherhood, V. Cookbook and Recipes.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3780. Acquired 2012-10-06
Related Resources
Related references
Find a Grave, Inc. "Mamie E. Boone." Memorial #83857894. Databases. Accessed 2017 December 18.
Find a Grave, Inc. "Mary Cole Boone." Memorial #83858728. Databases. Accessed 2017 December 18.
Smyrl, Vivian Elizabeth. "Waco University." Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2017 December 18.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Boone, Mamie -- Archives.; Boone, Mary Cole -- Archives.
Subjects (Organizations)
NoZe Brotherhood (Waco, Tex.) -- Photographs.; Waco University -- Records and correspondence.
Places
Europe -- Pictorial works.
Subjects
Cooking -- United States.; High schools -- Texas -- Dallas -- Scrapbooks.; Postcards.; Presidents -- Homes and haunts -- United States -- Photographs.
Genres
Reports.
- School and Literary Materials, 1867-1957; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains bound and loose poetry and other literary materials, including a Dallas Texas high school scrapbook. This series is in average condition.
  - School Materials (1 of 2), 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - School Materials (2 of 2), 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Poetical Works of William Cowper, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Quotations and Notes Scrapbook (1 of 3), circa 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Quotations and Notes Scrapbook (2 of 3), circa 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Quotations and Notes Scrapbook (3 of 3), circa 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Poetry scrapbook, circa 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - High School Graduation scrapbook, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Travel, 1941, 1960; 2
  General condition: Good.
  This series contains materials on Boone's numerous travels during summers, when she had time off work from her job as a school principal in Dallas, Texas. Included in this series is an extensive number of postcards she collected of various places she visited in Europe. This series is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Postcards
  - Trip to Europe loose materials, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (1 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (2 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (3 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (4 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (5 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Trip to Europe postcards (6 of 6), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "A Sundial Record of a Six Week Motor Trip", 1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Trip to Europe notebook, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mary Cole Boone, 1876-1916, undated; 3
  General condition: Poor.
  This series contains correspondence, Waco University speeches, poetry, photographs, and other materials from Mary Cole Boone, Mamie Boone's mother. This series is in poor condition.
  Photographic print
  - Correspondence, 1876-1882 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1883 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1883 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1892-1897 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1898-1916, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Waco University monthly reports (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Waco University Speech, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Resolutions, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Poetry and Prose, circa 1873 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- NoZe Brotherhood, 2006; 4
  General condition: Excellent.
  This series contains materials on the dedication of an elevator at Baylor University's Student Life Center by the NoZe Brotherhood. These materials appear to have been sent to Mamie Boone. This series is in excellent condition.
  - NoZe Bortherhood elevator dedication and float, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Cookbook and Recipes, 1915; 5
  This series contains loose recipes and The White House Cook Book. This series is in poor condition.
  - Loose Recipes from front of "The White House Cook Book", circa 1915 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The White House Cook Book, circa 1915 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 1)